<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Real_estate | Kevin Coleman]]></title>
  <link href="http://www.kcoleman.me/blog/categories/real-estate/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://www.kcoleman.me/"/>
  <updated>2015-01-29T00:18:18-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://www.kcoleman.me/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Kevin Coleman]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Buying My First Real Estate Investment]]></title>
    <link href="http://www.kcoleman.me/blog/2014/07/28/new-house/"/>
    <updated>2014-07-28T12:46:17-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://www.kcoleman.me/blog/2014/07/28/new-house</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://www.kcoleman.me/images/city-houses.jpg" title="First Real Estate Investment Property" class="banner-img"  /></p>

<p>This week I will be closing on my first house that I plan on renovating and selling in the next few months.  I have been looking for a low-end flip for over a year now and I finally found one via <a href="http://networthrealtyusa.com/">NetWorth Reality</a> in Atlanta.</p>

<p>Throughout this year long process, I have learned tons about the Atlanta real estate market and in general what to look for in purchasing an investment property.</p>

<p>My criteria for my first purchase has been:</p>

<ol>
<li>The property value + $15k (for wiggle room) must be within my budget</li>
<li>No seriously large repairs should be necessary. (roof and foundation need to be in good condition)</li>
<li>Near my residence</li>
<li>Low crime neighborhood.</li>
<li>Zoned for good schools.</li>
<li><a href="http://Zillow.com">Zillow</a> and comparable houses needed agree on the value of the home*.</li>
<li>Best-case estimated profit needs to be at least $15,000.</li>
<li>Must be able to be sold quickly at a higher value</li>
<li>No condos (typically have high Homeowners Association fees and renting restrictions)</li>
</ol>


<p>The house I am buying meets most of the criteria, although its location is about 30 minutes away one direction.  As a developer that sells his time, I am not excited about having to drive that on a weekly (daily?!) basis, but I plan on outsourcing as much of the property management that I can.</p>

<p>Once the repairs are finished on the property, I want to sell this property as soon as I can, because I don&rsquo;t have time to manage renters or property repairs.  While I already have interest from one person to rent from the house,</p>

<p>Hopefully this will be a profitable endeavor, but it could just end up being an expensive learning experience.</p>

<ul>
<li>While I agree that <a href="http://Zillow.com">Zillow</a> doesn&rsquo;t know what it is talking about when it comes to home values.  I also think that the people buying the homes would not want to purchase a house too far off the price listed online.  The house I bought Zillow thinks is worth $115k and I purchased it for $47k.</li>
</ul>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
